

# Pablo Obando Senior Full Stack Engineer

I'm a passionate full stack developer from SJ, Costa Rica. With over 6 years of experience developing web and mobile apps, focused on improving user experiences and ensuring top-notch UI code quality in all project processes.

I collaborate with teams to drive software product development, guiding technical decisions from concept to production, and ensuring successful project execution.

You can learn more about me on my website.

# Work Experience

JUNE 2021 - AUGUST 2023

#### Senior Full Stack Developer @ Parsley Health

At Parsley Health, a healthcare company that focuses on providing personalized and holistic primary care services, I collaborated on impactful projects ensuring timely and budget-compliant deliveries. As part of my responsibilities:

- Collaborate on the <u>website</u> migration from wordpress to gatsby, including the creation of react components in a storybook for use across multiple websites.
- Collaborate in the development and ongoing maintenance of core <u>checkout flow</u>, enabling users to effortlessly purchase a membership. Additionally, led implementation of Cypress tests throughout all purchase pathways, guaranteeing thorough testing coverage.
- Implement A/B testing tools and methodologies to drive optimization and glean valuable insights considering user metrics to discern user preferences and behaviors to achieve organizational goals.
- Creation and implementation of endpoints using grpc and graphql, enabling users to have full control over their medical appointments.

typescript react.js node.js graphql next.js tailwind aws

JULY 2019 - JUNE 2021

#### Full Stack Developer @ Quext

At Quext, a property management platform designed to empower managers and leasing agents by streamlining workflows and automating tasks, all with the goal of elevating property value and enhancing the resident experience. As part of my responsibilities:

- Collaborate in the creation from scratch of an <u>app</u> that empower individuals to find the perfect apartment that suits their needs.
- Drove improvements to enhance the user experience and functionality of a property

- rental application.
- The development and maintenance of a content management system (cms) enabling property owners to effortlessly manage their residences.
- Design, and development of API's.

typescript react.js node.js nest.js vue.js tailwind postgresql

JUNE 2018 - JUNE 2019

#### Full Stack Developer @ Bananacode

At Bananacode, a software agency. I started as a back end developer and later transitioned into a full stack role, as part of my responsibilities:

- Led a backend project with four developers for <u>delfino.cr</u>.
- Develop a flexible subscription system, to monetize based on content access.
- Development of cms for ecommerce, to enable managers to gain valuable insights.
- Creation and maintenance of web components in a storybook.

typescript react.js react native node.js graphql mongo.db mysql

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2018

## Front End Developer @ Nw Ideas

At NW Ideas a digital agency. I collaborated on challenging projects immersing myself in react and react native, as part of my responsibilities:

- Creation of landing pages from scratch with a variety of css libraries.
- Collaborate in the development of a bank's score app for <u>davivienda</u>.

javascript react.js react native php css3

#### Education

MAY 2017 - 2020

### Computer Engineering @ Fidélitas University

javascript python mob programming oop solid

#### Stack

```
mongodb express node.js graphQl mysql aws apollo
react.js gatsby cypress tailwind next jest react native
docker github gitlab codecommit docker
```

